

South Brisbane, Brisbane, QLD 4101, Australia

□ (+61) 411-980-632 | **mingzhe.zhang@uq.edu.au**

Summary_

I am currently a master's student at the University of Queensland (UQ) with scholarship support (Summer Research Scholarship). My GPA is 6.33/7.0 and is awarded Dean's Commendation for Academic Excellence. Before joining UQ, I received my bachelor's degree from Shanxi University (a "Double First-Class" University in China, universities and disciplines are recognised at the world-class level by the Ministry of Education of China) in 2019. My current research interests include machine learning and its applications in the medical domain.

In the last one year, I have produced two first-author publications, including one journal paper- Journal Machine Learning (Core A) and a conference paper - 18th International Conference Advanced Data Mining and Applications (Core B). In addition, I have actively participate research project and gain teaching experience, I worked as a research assistant on multiple projects at UQ, and I was employed as a tutor for INFS3202/7202 Web Information System with positive feedback from the course coordinator and students.

Education

Master of Engineering Science (Software Engineering)

Brisbane, Australia

Feb. 2022 - Feb. 2023

THE UNIVERSITY OF QUEENSLAND

- GPA: 633/7
- Dean's Commendation for Academic Excellence

Bachelor of Software Engineering

Taiyuan, China

Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2019

SHANXI UNIVERSITY

- GPA: 84 / 100
- Represented the university in a Semi-Pro E-sports League and won the **Championship**

Publication

- M. Zhang, L. Yue, M. Xu. "ESTD: Empathy Style Transformer with Discriminative mechanism." Accepted by The 18th International Conference
 - on Advanced Data Mining and Applications (ADMA'22). (CORE B, First Author, Accepted)

 In this work, Mingzhe contributed to designing and implementing the proposed Empathy Style Transformer with Discriminative mechanism (ESTD). This is the first work on the empathy style transfer using transformer.
- S. Shen, **M. Zhang**, W. Chen, A. Bialkowski, M. Xu. "Words Can be Confusing: Stereotype Bias Removal in Text Classification at the Word Level." The 27th PACIFIC-ASIA Conference On Knowledge Discovery And Data Mining (PAKDD 23) (**CORE A, Accepted**)
 - In this paper, Mingzhe contributed to designing and implementing the proposed mehtod, and conceived and conducted the experiments to get the results, and analyzed the experiment results.
- Y. Zhao, M. Zhang, C. Zhang, W. Chen, Y. Nan, M. Xu. "A Boosting Algorithm for Positive-Unlabeled Learning." Accepted by Springer Machine Learning Journal. (CORE A, Co-First Author, Accepted)
- In this paper, Mingzhe as co-first author contributed to implementing the proposed boosting algorithm for PU learning, conceived and conducted the experiments to get the results, and analyzed the experiment results.

Research Experience _____

Towards positive emotion: artificial intelligence-based expression rephrasing

Brisbane, Australia

May. 2022 - Dec. 2022

UQAI ECR Project in The University of Queensland

· Sentiment in language expression is one critical factor that impacts mental health. Compared to harsh or aggressive expressions, expressions with a high empathetic level can produce positive emotions. Unfortunately, non-empathetic expressions are generated every day, even without intention, causing negative feelings. This project aims to develop an advanced technique that upon receiving a language expression in text form can automatically evaluate its empathetic level and rephrase it such that the resulting text conveys the same meaning but with a higher empathetic level. The outcome of this project will be a prototype communication tool that in the future could help create a friendly and inclusive online environment if used in communication such as emails or instant messages.

A Boosting Algorithm for Learning from Positive-Unlabelled Data

Brisbane, Australia

Nov. 2021 - Feb. 2022

SUMMER RESEARCH PROJECT IN THE UNIVERSITY OF QUEENSLAND

- Machine learning is one of the major players in the AI-enabled economy according to Australia's AI Action Plan 2021.
- This project aims to develop a boosting-style machine learning methodology when only positive and unlabelled data is available. This novel methodology will be adapted to cyber security problems as an application.
- Be awarded the summer research scholarship at UQ

Service and Social Activity

Academic Conference Reviewer

Brisbane, Australia

THE 6TH APWEB-WAIM INTERNATIONAL JOINT CONFERENCE ON WEB AND BIG DATA, CORE B

May. 2022 - May. 2022

• Reviewer for the Industry-Track

Candidate for Postgraduate Coursework Student Member

Aug. 2022

UQ ACADEMIC BOARD AND COMMITTEES

• Join the Academic Board Elections Briefing session.

• Nomination for Postgraduate Coursework Student Member.

Brisbane, Australia

Volunteer Service for coal mine wastewater treatment

Shanxi, China

SHANXI COKING COAL GROUP CO.,LTD.

Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2019

• Assist staff in completing quality testing of industrial wastewater from coal mines.

Work Experience_

Research Assistant Brisbane, Australia

THE UNIVERSITY OF QUEENSLAND

May. 2022 - Dec. 2022

• Text style transfer: Developed an advanced technique that upon receiving a language expression in text form can automatically evaluate its empathetic level and rephrase it such that the resulting text conveys the same meaning but with a higher empathetic level.

- Empathy Detection: Implemented classification model for detecting empathy utterance with adversarial training and PU learning methods.
- Design algorithms that can enlarge the labeled empathy dataset from other data resources without the empathy label.
- · Develop a prototype system to integrate all developed techniques, with a showcase of its performance.

Data Analyst Beijing, China

QIANFENG EDUCATION GROUP

Feb. 2019 - Jun. 2019

- User Repurchase Forecast: Predict the probability of repeat purchases by processing and analyzing the user's shopping preferences and the importance of the item.
- E-commerce data analysis and mining project: Analyze e-commerce data and use time series models (RNN, LSTM and GRU) to predict the hotness of products in different quarters.

Teaching Experience

Tutor (INFS3202/7202 Web Information System)

Brisbane, Australia

THE UNIVERSITY OF QUEENSLAND

Feb. 2022 - Jun. 2022

• Assist the Course Coordinator for tutorial delivering, assignment marking, final exam marking, and student consultation.

Honors & Awards.

2022	Dean's Commendation for Academic Excellence, Semester 1, 2022	Brisbane, Australia
2021	Summer Research Scholarship, in summer semester at UQ	Brisbane, Australia
2017	Dux of the program, Shanxi University	Taiyuan, China
2017	1st Winner, 2017 Overwatch CSL (Provincial League) Shanxi	Taiyuan, China
2017	1st Winner , 2017 Overwatch CSL (City League) Taiyuan	Taiyuan, China
2017	1st Winner, 2017 Overwatch NSC (City League) Taiyuan	Taiyuan, China

Skills

- Programming Languages: Python, PHP, C/C ++, JAVA, C#, and JavaScript
- Data Analysis Tools: Oracle, PostgreSQL, Spark, MonkeyLearn
- Machine Learning Tools: Pytorch, TensorFlow, Caffe, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Scikit-Learn
- Experienced Fields: Natural Language Processing, PU Learning, Boosting Algorithm, Time Series Prediction, and Causality
- Other Skills: Back-End Development, Linux, Web Design, UI Design, and Graphic Design